(Maximum Happiness)
Nice to see you all.
We're going to bring in the star of the Rainbow Live.
A lot of people were surprised that this star would join our show.
I didn't expect her to join our show.
Because she rarely stars on TV shows.
- That's right. - Has anyone crossed paths with her?
I recently met her on a radio show.
She's calmer than I expected.
- She is calm. - That's right.
Actually, I've never met anyone wittier with words than her.
With her natural sense of humor and ability to deliver her acts,
she's an MC, an excellent radio DJ, and a great actress.
She's a true all-rounder who's versatile in many fields.
It's Member Kim Shin Young!
- Hello. - My gosh.
(Welcome to the show.)
(Bowing)
(She became a national sister with her catchphrase, "Brother.")
(Acting cute)
(A woman with 1,000 faces and unparalleled charms)
(A legit comedienne with a solid career of 23 years)
I hope you like my show.
(And her another success, her career as an experienced DJ)
Let's go!
(The best DJ who won numerous awards...)
(and boosted the ratings with her flawless hosting skills)
(She became a muse for Director Park Chan Wook...)
(in his movie, "Decision to Leave.")
(She's a talented actress who won...)
(the Best Supporting Actress...)
(at the Korean Film Producers Association Awards.)
(She used to be an iconic figure of weight-loss 13 years ago...)
(after losing 44kg.)
(She's back in her initial state with her weighty body.)
(The versatile entertainer, Kim Shin Young)
- Gosh, I can't believe this. - Hello.
- Hello. - Welcome.
Please stand in the middle.
- Say hello to our viewers. - Okay.
Hello.
I've been living alone for 14 years.
I'm a comedienne, Kim Shin Young. Nice to meet you.
(Comedienne Kim Shin Young)
(Exhaling)
How does it feel to be in our studio?
It's smaller than I expected.
- Everyone says that. - It is.
I naturally assumed that...
- you had been on the show before. - Okay.
I found out today that this was her first appearance.
- It's my first time here. - Right.
- She rarely comes out of her house. - Right.
- But we're introverts too. - Right.
So you'll feel at ease here.
- I'm an introvert too. - Everyone on our show is calm.
- Really? - Yes.
What made you decide to star on our show?
I always wanted to star on this show at least once.
And I never had a chance to look at my day-to-day life like this.
It's just another day for me.
But I had never observed my days.
So I decided to star on the show.
I was curious about your lifestyle.
She's somewhat of a mystery even in the entertainment industry.
- Right. - I'm curious about her lifestyle.
- I rarely come out of the house. - Right.
She's the biggest homebody I know.
All right. I wonder what she does at home.
She'll reveal her day-to-day life for the first time on TV.
(Let's take a look at Homebody Shin Young's life.)
(Happiness Is Bound to Return)
(Shin Young is sleeping in a dark bedroom.)
- Right, you have blackout curtains. - I do.
(Fascinated)
So that's how I look.
(Throwing)
(She clumsily kicks the pillow.)
I have to stretch.
- That's it? - Yes.
- What? - It was brief, but I did it.
(It was brief.)
It ended in a flash.
In a flash?
She's cute.
(A lightning-speed stretch)
(I should get up now.)
(Struggling)
(She makes the bed as soon as she gets up.)
- You make your bed right away. - I must do it as soon as I get up.
(Spraying)
My goodness. What are you spraying?
Scented mite spray.
- Really? - Yes.
- I also spray that. - It's an absolute must.
The next time I use it,
- the blanket feels fresh. - Right.
- But then... - It's an absolute must.
The dead bodies of the mites must be on your blanket.
- I have a separate pad... - You know?
Underneath my bed.
Really?
Do you have a lot of mites in your house?
I mean, I'm human too.
- Mites... - Right.
- Well, mites... - Do you guys...
talk a lot about mites like this?
We're very interested in other people's lifestyles.
- We are. - Okay.
We'll ask you a lot of questions today like what you spray and so on.
- I'm very interested. - Right.
For some reason, I think she'll have a lot of wise life tips.
Exactly. She's been on her own for 14 years.
- I have many tips. - Do you spray that on here?
- Right. Spray it on your chest. - The mite spray?
I spray it here before I spray it on my blanket.
- I shake them down. - Come on.
(Exterminating mites)
- Hyun Moo. - It's like the Amazon there.
Don't use the spray. Just burn them.
My gosh. Burn them?
- Like this. - No.
I don't get my chest hair waxed.
(Precious)
(After her morning routine of getting rid of mites...)
(Trudging out)
- Gosh. - Her house looks hip.
(A hip living room)
Her living room has a different vibe.
I see a lot of stuff.
(They're spotted in every corner.)
She loves colorful accessories.
- I love colorful accessories. - Yes.
This looks like a room of an idol star.
(Another room in Shin Young's house)
You have so many clothes.
My dream is to turn my dressing room into a clothing showroom.
It does look like a clothing shop.
- Like a clothing shop in Japan. - Right.
- There's more? - Yes.
(The second room after the dressing room)
It's in the back. I call it the Denim Room.
Denim Room?
- My gosh. - She has a separate room for denim?
- You have a Denim Room? - No way.
I love denim.
Any piece of clothing with denim...
- goes straight to the Denim Room. - She has so many clothes.
I was in Japan...
- and shopping for denim clothes. - Yes.
I saw an old denim piece from Brand L.
- Yes. - From Levi's.
It was completely faded,
- but it cost 5,000 dollars. - What?
- Then... - Right.
- it must be from its early days. - It's from the early days.
Why does it cost that much?
The fabric is different.
Each year has different labels too.
They're all different. You're paying for its history.
To me, they were all the same jeans.
The only difference to me was about the depth of color.
Then do you have an expensive denim piece there?
I do.
- I have a piece... - Okay.
- with a five-figure price. - Really?
- Five figures? - Yes.
That's amazing.
So that's the second room.
Then I also have a separate room for shoes which had been my goal.
- For real? - Yes.
Her house is like a select shop.
- Aren't they all limited editions? - Yes.
(All of the walls...)
(are covered with shoes.)
(Nike, Collaboration Zone)
- Oh, that Nike pair! - Which one?
That's an expensive pair.
The first editions are really rare.
Right.
I feel at ease since you know a lot about this.
- I got you today. - Okay.
(They're kept in perfect condition, free of any stains.)
It's really hard to keep them in clean condition like that.
You just collect them, right? You don't wear them.
No. I wear them.
- I do. - They look brand-new.
I rarely step on the ground.
(I rarely step on the ground.)
- What? - What?
- I don't step on dirt. - My gosh.
What's the point of going through that trouble?
They make me happy.
- Hold on. - My gosh.
- They make me happy. - Really?
Of course.
(Yasuhiro Zone)
- Yasuhiro. - Yasuhiro.
- These are handmade sneakers. - You have so many cute pairs.
This is on another level. It's like a museum.
Don't you have thousands of pairs?
I stopped counting the pairs...
- after I hit 700 pairs. - Then you have over 1,000 pairs.
- Probably. - Right.
I have a brother who's three years older than me.
When I was a kid, I had to wear his old sneakers.
My parents couldn't afford...
to buy me the sneakers I wanted.
I thought I should buy sneakers when I could afford them.
So I worked at a barbecue restaurant in high school.
I saved up money and bought sneakers.
I bought them in high school.
- That's when you started. - The old pairs. You know, right?
Those old pairs are actually more valuable.
- Right. - There's a story behind that.
I bought them when they were about 300 dollars.
Now, it's in the five-figure price.
- Right. That's crazy valuable now. - Yes.
I could probably buy this house if I were to sell all of them.
But just the thought of selling them...
How can I sell my own babies? No.
(How can I sell my own babies?)
(She goes to Wilson with her phone.)
(Clicking)
It was my first time seeing Wilson in person.
That was a fascinating moment.
Wilson is here.
(I can't believe Wilson is in my house.)
(She goes to the kitchen after a brief meeting with Wilson.)
(Rattling)
- What's that? - Rice?
- Rice? - It's rice.
- You cook at home. - I do.
I have the biggest appetite in the morning.
Let's say I have to wake up at 4am.
Then I must be up by 3am and have my meal.
- Really? - She's so diligent.
- Of course. - Not a lot of people...
have an appetite in the morning.
Not me.
Then you must have a light dinner.
No, I also enjoy my dinner.
I have a huge appetite in the morning.
And dinner is just tasty.
They're different.
Dinner is delicious.
You have an appetite throughout the day.
- I'm busy during lunchtime. - It's the same thing.
(I have a voracious appetite in the morning.)
(Pouring out)
(She gets ready to wash the rice right away.)
She's washing the rice. That's a hassle.
There's the delicious smell...
- of freshly cooked rice. - Yes, I know.
I need my house to smell like freshly cooked rice in the morning.
(She drains the water after the first rinse.)
(She fills it up with water again.)
(Grabbing)
(This time, she pours the water into her tumbler.)
You have to use the water after the third rinse.
If you only rinse it once, it will be a bit stale.
- She sounds like an expert. - She is an expert.
(Putting it in the fridge right away)
(This should do it.)
(After checking the amount of water, she places it in the rice cooker.)
The keep-warm mode is off.
Okay.
I bet you didn't cook...
- when you were on a diet. - I did.
- Then how did you lose weight? - Maybe, she ate less.
No. I don't add brown rice anymore.
I used to mix brown rice with white rice.
I stopped mixing brown rice...
- and have been eating white rice. - You eat white rice.
And rice tastes so good.
- White rice? - It melts in my mouth.
- Is white rice that fattening? - I don't even have to chew.
I can just swallow it.
- I bet. - My gosh. No way.
When you start craving white rice,
it's a sign that you'll gain 5kg.
Right. White rice is tasty, but it's fattening.
(Opening)
(Her fridge is neatly organized.)
- You have a lot of side dishes. - My fridge is clean.
(Reaching)
(She grabs a side dish container without hesitation.)
- I'm curious what she'll eat. - So...
(Rummaging through)
(She places a pot on the stove first.)
Oh, right.
(She opens the side dish container.)
- What's that? - What is it?
- My gosh. That looks so good. - For breakfast?
You marinated it beforehand.
(Here's beef bulgogi she marinated the day before.)
(Humming)
I always prepare my breakfast late at night the day before.
If I'm craving bulgogi, I marinate some beef.
I even make zucchini jeon the day before too.
So I can take them out next morning and eat my breakfast right away.
My evening has to be exhausting to have a happy morning.
She's so diligent.
(While thanking yesterday's me...)
(for making this morning's me happy...)
I've never seen anyone who lives alone...
marinate beef for bulgogi.
I must eat a lot of meat for breakfast.
(She transfers a lot of marinated beef to the pot.)
(Generously pouring the sauce)
Do you add any special ingredient to the marinade?
I add apple juice.
I drizzle apple juice over the meat.
That way, it tenderizes the meat before adding the marinade.
Besides, people eat apples for breakfast.
- So you added it to the marinade? - Right.
- Don't try to convince us. - For breakfast.
(Her logic almost convinced them.)
(She puts her bulgogi that makes perfect sense on the stove.)
(Pulling it out)
There's a sense of certainty in all of her movements.
(Laughing)
This too.
(She grabs the containers without a moment of hesitation.)
(She comes back with both hands full of side dishes.)
(Cucumber kimchi to boost her appetite)
- Cucumber kimchi? - Yes, cucumber kimchi.
- Did you... - She's amazing.
- I love it. - Seaweed stems.
- They're so good too. - You eat them when it's just you?
(She puts back the side dish containers.)
(Careful)
- I'm very careful with it. - What's that?
What is it? My gosh.
My gosh, it smells so good.
(Looking delicious in no time)
- The house must smell like bulgogi. - Right.
On top of the rice getting cooked.
(Opening)
- Glass noodles? - What?
- To put them in the bulgogi? - Yes.
Even restaurants wouldn't serve such heavy meals in the morning.
(Even restaurants wouldn't serve such heavy meals in the morning.)
I must always have glass noodles.
They must be cooked the moment I put them in.
Dried-up glass noodles will need time to be cooked.
I had this obsession back in the day.
"I should eat glass noodles instead of eating..."
"any other noodles or ramyeon."
But it's better to eat ramyeon.
Once you get hooked on glass noodles, you eat too much.
I even add glass noodles to ramyeon.
So I can't stop eating them.
There's nothing I can do.
Glass noodles are tasty...
- in every dish. - Right.
(She washes her hands thoroughly first.)
(Grabbing a handful of glass noodles)
(Adding them right into the pot)
That's quite fattening.
It's okay. They're made of sweet potato starch.
(Don't worry.)
I can't get used to this fridge.
(Adding the rice-rinsed water)
(I can't forget about this.)
(Reaching)
- It's black pepper. - Black pepper?
My gosh. That must be really tasty.
- Wait. Black pepper? - My gosh.
I'm Black Pepper Man.
(I'm Black Pepper Man.)
- The problem is I add too much. - I bet you hate ground pepper.
- I hate that. - The ground pepper.
That's useless. My gosh.
That's the OG black pepper.
- That's the OG black pepper. - That's the OG black pepper.
- That's it. - The finely ground black pepper.
(Generously sprinkling black pepper)
My gosh, this looks good.
Not a lot of people get to hear the rice cooker in the morning.
Seriously.
But it's a lovely sound.
- Right? - Yes.
(Let me check the seasoning.)
Nice.
Pho needs cilantro.
- Stew needs black pepper. - Right.
That's good.
(She washes the used pot immediately.)
She keeps it clean.
(Cleaning)
You can even use her sink to cook.
I use toothpaste and leftover salt to clean the sink.
- It's spotless then. - There aren't any water stains.
(Grabbing)
- What? - What's that?
- What is that? - My gosh.
- Seaweed soup. - Yes.
(Here's a dried block of seaweed soup.)
- I see. - The soup is...
You need some kind of soup no matter what.
I need soup.
(Her meal is almost ready.)
(Staring)
(Pouting)
Fourteen minutes.
The rice is taking longer than she thought.
- The timing was off. - I see.
Fourteen minutes.
(Scowling)
But what if the glass noodles get soggy?
I was so conflicted.
(A mental game against the rice cooker over glass noodles)
(A suffocating confrontation)
(Both of them are steaming.)
- What's going on? - She might smack the rice cooker.
(Sensitive)
(Time keeps passing amidst growing anxiety.)
(Her grand meal is getting cold without the rice.)
She's waiting until the rice is cooked.
- I would've eaten the bulgogi. - Same here.
Me too.
My gosh. It's taking way too long.
I started too early.
(She plops down on her chair, exhausted from hunger.)
(Yes. Let me pick out a video first.)
Is it baseball?
It was a highlight video from yesterday.
(Stirring)
She's going to eat.
- I ended up eating them first. - Glass noodles first.
- They get soggy. - Right.
(Slurping)
(Yes, this is what I'm talking about.)
Gosh, it looks so good.
My gosh, it's good.
(Getting a thrill)
I ate the noodles first before my rice was ready.
The glass noodles steal all the sauce.
So I started with the glass noodles.
It's a palate cleanser.
Like a dessert.
It's like a dessert?
(She's enjoying her dessert, the glass noodles, in the morning.)
Isn't that an appetizer?
Actually, desserts should be eaten before the meal.
Meals come after desserts.
- What? - That's how it is.
- Some do that to lose weight. - The order of the meal... Right.
- To delay the insulin spike? - Desserts first... Yes.
Do you only eat that type of glass noodles?
- Only those glass noodles. - The old-school one?
Yes, the old-school one.
- Wide ones don't taste the same. - I know. Wide ones...
- The ones that go into tteokbokki? - Yes.
Wide glass noodles can't soak up the sauce well.
- Even when you soak them in water, - Right.
I can finish them in a few bites.
They become the star of the dish.
Here's what I noticed about foodies.
I thought they'd be accepting of all food.
But they discriminate a lot.
- Right. We're very picky. - People...
- Discriminate? - People...
who aren't foodies would just eat anything.
We've tried all kinds of food and then found the best one.
- The best one. - We want the best for our meal.
You went through trial and error.
Of course. I've gone through trial and error.
(Getting a refill of her best glass noodles)
(Engrossed in the food)
(Grabbing)
(Crunchy)
(Refreshing cucumber kimchi as the palate cleanser)
(Humming)
I'm hungry.
- You're having it without the rice. - I was hungry.
- So it's Round One. - Yes.
Your delicious glutinous white rice is ready.
- At last. - My rice is cooked.
Great timing.
(At last!)
(Getting up)
I like having clean white rice.
- So the sauce doesn't get on it? - Right.
(She finally opens the rice cooker.)
Nice.
(She finally sees her white rice after a long wait.)
I love the smell of freshly cooked rice.
(Praying)
(Feeling solemn before the white rice)
She's solemn.
(Stirring)
(Dividing them into four sections in a sacred manner)
(Blowing)
Look at it. It's glistening and looks deliciously sticky.
(In a good mood)
I'll start my meal at last.
(Her breakfast begins in earnest.)
(Pulling closer)
(She's been looking forward to the white rice.)
It does look really good.
(Raised eyebrows)
(It's so good that her eyes open wide.)
The rice came out well.
I could finally see what's in front of me.
(She enjoys the classic combo, bulgogi with the rice.)
(She's enjoying her meal with each side dish.)
(Slurping)
She's eating with gusto.
I bet moms adore you.
(Quickly eating her meal with gusto)
(She has a sip of the warm seaweed soup.)
(Satisfied)
(Drinking up the seaweed soup as if it's unrefined makgeolli)
Why did they add a clip of Mo Pal Mo?
(A satisfied sigh)
(Gathering)
(She's almost done with bulgogi in no time.)
- You'll mix rice in it? - Yes.
So it's easier to wash them.
(Round 3, seaweed rice soup)
- Gosh, that looks good. - That looks good.
Having it with kimchi...
It's so good.
(Salivating)
(Gobbling up the food as if it's her first bite)
(Hitting the spot)
I went on a date with bulgogi and rice.
Then I finished it with seaweed soup.
It was an alms bowl meal.
(It was an alms bowl meal.)
People don't change.
Some say our constitution can change. That's all nonsense.
We always come back to it.
(We always come back to it in the end.)
What's the point of disciplining myself for 13 years?
It took three months.
- You gained weight fast. - Right.
I was like, "What's life?"
A chocolate cake was the starting point.
I eat whatever I crave.
I eat when I get hungry.
Back in the day, I was sensitive.
But I'm easygoing now.
Even when people step on my toes,
I wouldn't get so mad.
I've become more generous.
You've gotten gentle.
- She definitely changed. - Yes.
You were an iconic figure of losing weight...
up until a few years ago.
- Right. - Yes.
She used to say that she had to lose weight...
- to live a healthy life. - Right.
- Seriously. - My body might be healthy.
- But my mind wasn't so healthy. - I see.
I do respect you for this, though.
- What? - You lost weight...
during the toughest time...
- to lose weight. - Right.
- It's easier to lose weight now. - Right.
- But you won't take the easy way. - Right.
- Exactly. - You're right.
- You're right. - Yes.
- I... - You're so sharp.
- There are Wegovy and Mounjaro. - Right. Mounjaro.
- Wegovy. - I don't want to take them.
You're not tempted to take them?
No temptations.
- You're not tempted to take them? - No temptations.
- But what made you... - Really?
- decide to start bulking up? - Yes.
- Bulking up... - Bulk up?
- I didn't mean it like that. - Hold on.
- So is this how it goes here? - No.
- Is this "Show Me the Money?" - No.
His diss was ruthless.
Everyone has a good heart.
- Really? - They're not eloquent.
- Are we here to diss each other? - He's a good guy.
No. People bulk up first...
- before they build muscles. - Why...
Why would I need to build muscles?
- He didn't mean it like that. - Okay.
- I didn't mean to bulk up. - Okay.
Actually, I stayed...
by the late professor's side until his last moment.
- I'm talking about Jeon Yu Seong. - Jeon Yu Seong.
The professor said, "Hey, Shin Young."
"I'm really craving jjamppong."
"But I can't eat that now."
Then he said, "Don't waste your life denying yourself some good food."
"Eat whatever you want."
What he said resonated with me.
- I had been on a diet for 14 years. - Right.
I'd say things, "No. Not now."
- "I can't eat now." - Right.
"No bread for me." He saw me turn down food.
Toward the end, he told me to eat whatever I craved.
- He was right about that. - Right.
- Yes. - I decided not to be bothered...
by gaining weight. That's just me.
- I should still love myself. - Right.
So I ate everything I wanted.
That was the reason behind your story.
Right. I had a backstory to it.
(A heartwarming backstory to her weight gain)
That was good.
(Rattling)
(Wiping)
She's so clean.
I must clean them right away.
(She wipes the table while clearing the table.)
- I must clean them right away. - That's impressive.
That's one of the reasons I don't cook.
- Cleaning up is such a hassle. - It's a hassle.
- It's a big hassle. - A lot of people say that.
- If you do it right away, it's not. - Right.
- Really? - Yes.
(Let's see.)
- My gosh. - Nice.
- It's not good once it dries up. - Right.
(She tightly wraps up the leftover side dish.)
(She puts it in the fridge.)
Did you run a restaurant before?
I worked part-time at a jjajangmyeon restaurant.
When I worked there,
- I had to rip it with this hand. - The pickled radishes.
You used your hand blade?
I used my hand blade.
Using scissors would take too long.
- It takes too long. - You wrapped the food...
- and went on delivery runs? - Of course.
I'd wrap it up and deliver it.
I'd wrap up pickled radishes...
- in the morning. - Of course.
Then I'd grab one and deliver the food.
I'm quite good at driving a motorcycle.
You drove a motorcycle to deliver food?
I used to deliver food too.
(Impressed)
You're a true all-rounder.
(Amazed)
(Water gushing out)
(She washes the bowls and plates she used right away.)
You're washing them with bare hands.
- Right. - Without any gloves.
- I can't check if they're clean. - Right.
(Squeaky clean)
It became a habit of mine.
I'll be the one cleaning up.
I'll be the one throwing out the trash.
After watching TV...
and wasting my spare time,
it gets really hard to finish all my tasks at once.
Thinking about these tasks is stressful.
I'll have to do them anyway. Getting them done fast is the best.
When I can't get out of it, it's better to finish it fast.
(Turning off)
That was fast. She washes the dishes so fast.
I'm done.
What will you do next?
I'm very busy in the morning.
(Going through the upper cupboard)
(She takes out containers.)
My gosh. I forgot.
(She opens up the rice cooker.)
- I divide it into containers. - Rice?
- Right. - I see.
- Really? - Yes.
- You don't keep it in the cooker? - Or the rice gets dry.
- It gets dry and isn't tasty. - It doesn't taste good...
- after some time. - It turns yellow too.
Right.
It's fun to stock up on cooked rice too.
I transfer the rice into small containers on purpose.
- I see. - Okay.
- Why? - I don't eat that much rice.
Isn't it because you want the rice to get warm faster?
My gosh.
It's so tiny. It looks smaller in person.
(Surprised)
(She washes the rice cooker after portioning the rice.)
(She shakes off the water and finishes up.)
(Tearing the kitchen towel)
- What was that? - Hey.
You knew you almost pulled out the faucet, right?
(A sharp movement)
I have to be quick.
I'd run the water...
- and adjusted my hand speed. - Right.
- That's a waste of water. - I see.
- But she adjusted the water speed. - That's wasteful.
Right. I was dumb.
(Quick)
(She precisely gets a small amount of water on the kitchen towel.)
I clean the lid right away.
- The lid of the rice cooker. - It works better than wet wipes.
I can tell that she has done this many times.
You wipe the inside gently.
It's easier to do this than have a major clean-out.
(This time, she organizes the rice she has portioned out.)
You really seem like a soldier.
(Organized)
All done.
It's neat.
(She brushes her teeth to keep them clean.)
I'm busy.
That's tooth powder.
- Tooth powder. - People use it these days.
- It gets rid of plaques. - Mites?
- Mites? - Not mites.
- Hold on. - Why would there be mites?
- Mites on the teeth? - I'm not the "Predator" monster.
Why do you keep talking about mites?
(He has a lot of interest in the mites.)
(Gagging)
That's it. It's refreshing.
- I do it in a refreshing way. - You brush the nooks and crannies.
You stick the toothbrush in deep.
All right.
(Feeling refreshed, she heads to the kitchen.)
She is so diligent.
Seriously.
(Clattering)
(She begins to vacuum.)
(She vacuums under the rug.)
- She put on a hat. - Is that for vacuuming?
She looks hip.
(She wears a hat so that her hair won't fall.)
It isn't easy to look good in a short-brimmed hat.
(Whirring)
(She resumes vacuuming after locking her hair in a hat.)
The troublesome chores must be done 1st or 2nd.
It feels good when the house is clean.
It's especially true when you have a day off.
When trash is lying around,
and the air is stuffy, it gets so tiring.
What? How many are there?
It's "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory."
I also thought it was "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory."
- Seriously. - It really seems that way...
because she is wearing a hat.
You know, it's really eerie.
It's "Charlie and the Japchae Factory."
- Japchae. - It has that vibe.
- Glass noodle. - Glass noodle factory.
- Glass noodle factory. - Yes.
(The sanitation procedure is thorough...)
(at "Charlie and the Japchae Factory.")
(She vacuums every inch of the house.)
All done.
(She puts the vacuum back in its place.)
(Plopping down)
(Staring)
It's 2:30pm.
By 3pm...
(She gets back up after checking the time.)
(Opening)
Let's see.
- Oh, my. It's completely full. - There are so many shoes.
I see a lot of shoes.
It'd be impossible to know what kind of shoes you have.
I know every single pair.
(Let's see.)
Here.
- This one is full too. - This one has shoes too.
(It's also full of shoes.)
There are daily shoes...
as well as shoes of different purposes.
(Humming)
I pick a pair in my head.
- You pick a pair you'll wear. - Yes.
I'm amazed that you remember...
- every pair. - I know.
When shoes are organized that way,
- some pairs never get worn. - Right.
- When they're stashed that way... - We do that.
We do that. That's right.
I sort them every season.
I see.
I do that to make sure no pair is forgotten.
- You switch their positions. - Yes.
(She walks over somewhere with a pair of shoes.)
(A mysterious spot in a corner of the living room)
Okay.
- Oh, my. Inside her house? - What's that?
(There are a sewing machine and scissors...)
(as well as fabric and threads of various colors.)
That's fascinating.
It was my wish.
I separated the spot using the display cabinets.
I can adjust the size...
and upcycle clothes here.
It's my private workroom.
It's very cozy.
- It seems like a different room. - I know.
(The box is filled with fabric scraps.)
- There must be a lot of denim. - Yes.
Do you buy things at Dongdaemun?
Those are the fabric scraps I got when I repaired clothes.
- Are those the hems? - The hems and...
- Scraps from repairing clothes. - Yes.
There are fabric scraps from my pajamas...
and white T-shirts. I collect the cut pieces.
- Right. You don't need to buy them. - That's right.
(Grabbing)
(She takes out the red thread after the fabric.)
There are threads in red and darker red.
- The colors are different. - Yes. Completely different.
(On the desk are the sewing tools and sneakers.)
I customized the sneakers.
- Oh, my. - They're my works,
- No way. You're really good. - Oh, my.
I sewed them with my hands.
- Your skills are extraordinary. - They're in different styles.
In most cases, I renew...
the items I haven't worn a lot.
You give them a new life.
(The one and only Kim Shin Young collection)
Since people wear the same shoes,
I customize them. I have...
- seven design patents. - My goodness.
(She has 7 design patents from customizing shoes.)
It's what I do for fun.
I always have a strong creative drive.
I want to make new things...
or come up with new ideas.
Otherwise, I want to meet new people and make them laugh.
I have a creative drive.
- She is cool. - So...
I've been working on one pair of shoes at a time.
It has been four years.
- That's really cool. - She is really cool.
It's a healthy hobby.
(Grabbing)
I have a question. Do you go with the design...
that enters your head when you look at the sneakers?
Do you come up with the design beforehand?
I think it through in my head and get to work right away.
- You're an artist. - There are no plans.
- There are no plans. - No.
That means you're born with a talent.
(She customizes the shoes without any design plans.)
(She uses eyeball measurements to cut the other side.)
(Let's see.)
How do you even come up...
with the idea to cut out that part and put different fabric on it?
I have a desire to think differently.
She is an artist.
- She can picture it in her head. - That's right.
- She is an artist. - How fascinating.
That's it.
(Grabbing)
It isn't a regular thimble.
- There is steel inside. - Okay.
- It helps you press... - That's right.
- That's right. - with more force.
The rubber thimble is for sticking out the needle.
It keeps the needle from slipping.
Let's go.
(She begins to work on the design that's in her head.)
(She puts fabric against the top cap...)
(and sews it in.)
I've altered clothes before,
but it's my first time seeing someone do it with shoes.
(Staring intently)
(She sews shoes expertly even though they're thick.)
(She quietly becomes absorbed in customizing her shoes.)
I should try it too.
(He attempted to customize shoes, )
(but failed spectacularly.)
(He renews his artistic soul.)
(She enjoys customizing shoes at her workroom in the corner.)
(She stays rooted to the place for a while.)
(It has been an hour since she began working.)
- No other pairs in the world. - Right.
People who want to customize shoes...
try it, but lack the skills.
- That's right. - They mess up the shoes.
- I've messed up many shoes. - Same here.
(One stitch at a time)
(She combines various patterns...)
(and diverse colors.)
All done.
(All done.)
(Before the customization, the white sneakers looked simple.)
- Oh, my. - My goodness.
(What's the one and only pair Shin Young has made?)
All done.
(All done.)
(Before the customization, the white sneakers looked simple.)
- Oh, my. - My goodness.
- That's insane. - Oh, my.
She is really talented.
(With detailed sewing)
It's pretty.
(The one and only pair has been born.)
I'm wearing customized shoes.
They're quite detailed.
- She must've stitched the front... - Yes.
- by herself. - Yes.
- It's beyond the hobby level. - Seriously.
- I really enjoy it. - You're really good.
Because the sneakers are white,
the red lines look pretty.
- They used to be completely white. - Yes.
The added red lines make them fun.
The design patents involve some patterns.
My signature patterns.
- The triangular shape. - Yes, there are triangles...
and details...
in the back.
My goodness. Okay.
- Right. - Unbutton your pants.
Gosh, I did.
(This time, she grabs the pajamas.)
The pajamas too?
I have pajamas,
but they're bound to be long for me.
They need to be altered,
but it's a hassle to take them to an alteration service each time.
(She grabs the utility knife.)
(She cuts into it using eyeball measurements.)
- You don't take measures. - No.
(Then she sets the fabric aside.)
I know it right away.
"If this is the length,"
"it'll come up to here." I get a sense of it.
You know right away when you've done it dozens of times.
- You've done it multiple times. - That's right.
(Grabbing the top)
(Turning)
(Concentrating)
(She straightens the sleeves expertly.)
(This is the length of my arms.)
- That's a nice knife. - You can cut fabric at once.
Most people use an alteration service.
- The ends need to be sewn. - It's hard to do that.
I can't go there all the time.
(She pulls over a sewing machine.)
A sewing machine?
I've used it.
- That machine? - It's really hard.
-The sewing machine? - Yes.
- You get better at it. - It's really hard to use.
(She threads it expertly.)
(She turns over and folds the ends of the sleeves.)
If you fold them twice,
you won't get any lint. It's convenient.
(She slides it into the sewing machine.)
(She turns on the sewing machine.)
- It looks like a good one. - My goodness.
(Pursing her lips)
(She turns into a seamstress.)
From a Chinese restaurant to an alteration service...
- She does everything at home. - I know.
(She quickly finishes altering her pajamas.)
All done.
All right.
(She changes into the altered pajamas right away.)
I cut them well.
Finished.
- All done. - The length is just right.
It's just right. It's the perfect length.
It'll be nice...
- to alter clothes as you want. - All done.
Let's change again.
(After altering clothes, it's 6pm.)
(A cutting sound)
It sounds like she's slicing something.
(Slicing)
- What's this? - Radish?
Is that a radish?
(She begins preparing a radish without getting a break.)
The person who customized the shoes is gone.
- We're seeing a different person. - Her profession keeps changing.
- That person went home. - She went home.
You know, every tool suits her.
(The chef appears.)
(This is enough.)
My goodness.
It's tasty.
(The end goes into her mouth.)
Gosh, it's sweet.
(Salivating)
Its sweet flavor filled my mouth.
(Let's get up.)
(She enters the kitchen with radish in her mouth.)
(Grabbing a handful)
You'll make radish rice, right?
- Radish rice? - Radish rice.
(She puts the pot on the stove.)
(Rushing over)
(What will she do?)
(Taking out)
(She gets the necessary ingredients from the fridge.)
It's rice water from the morning.
- You'll use it. - You use it well.
(She takes out the rice water she has saved...)
(and pours it over the julienned radish.)
For dinner, I'll have cheonggukjang...
and spicy radish.
- Spicy radish? - Yes.
When you make cheonggukjang,
you should add spicy radish instead of diced radish.
When you add it early on, the radish will get cooked fast.
- The sweetness will seep out. - The vegetable broth.
- The vegetable broth will seep out. - Right.
You're more trustworthy than most chefs.
- Seriously. - I should've brought it.
- She has certainty in her work. - Yes.
That's right.
(With certainty, she prepares the next ingredient.)
(She grabs a peeled onion.)
(Taking out)
(She cuts it in half with all her might.)
(Slicing)
Gosh, she has incredible knife skills.
I've cooked since second grade.
(She slices an onion in no time.)
- Will you eat all of it? - Of course.
You saw multiple people in her house earlier.
- You're right. - There were many people.
One worked on the shoes.
(That's right. I need to feed all of them.)
(The chef is busy cooking for multiple people.)
(She tears lettuce with her hands to add a homely taste.)
(She adds the cheonggukjang sauce.)
(She tears mushrooms along the grain.)
The vegetable broth will seep out.
It looks delicious.
(While cheonggukjang boils, )
(she rummages through the fridge again.)
Where did it go? What?
(Suddenly, an alarm goes off for 6:25pm.)
What is the alarm for?
- It's an important alarm. - Five minutes.
It's the end of her shift.
A-3.
- It's the end of her shift. - Come on in.
(Here comes A-3.)
(The tasks are divided at the glass noodle factory.)
(Pressing the remote)
Baseball?
The game was scheduled for 6:30pm.
That's right. The evening game.
(She set an alarm for a baseball match.)
You'll watch it when it airs.
(Kneeling)
(Please let my team win today.)
I prayed with devotion in my heart.
(She prays for victory with devotion in her heart.)
(She rushes over after praying.)
I think I'm ready.
- My goodness. - Gosh.
I need to wear it.
I need to wear the uniform before the game begins.
(With the baseball channel on, she heads back to the fridge.)
(Taking out)
(She takes out a familiar container with care.)
- Glass noodles? - I think so.
That's right.
She's addicted to glass noodles.
I grabbed only a bit. You saw that, right?
- Charlie and glass noodle factory. - I grabbed only a bit, right?
I feel bad for the glass noodles.
I grabbed only a bit.
But glass noodles don't go well with cheonggukjang.
Of course, they do.
- I've never seen that combination. - Me neither.
Do people add glass noodles to cheonggukjang?
- I've never seen it. - They're for...
seolleongtang and gomtang.
As you add thin noodles to seolleongtang,
you add glass noodles to cheonggukjang.
I guess she adds them whenever there's moisture.
(I guess she adds them whenever there's moisture.)
- No. - Moisture isn't a must.
She adds them even when there's no moisture.
Are you talking about an aquatic animal?
- Moisture, my foot. - Seriously.
I'll add a bit to cheonggukjang.
I only added a bit.
(She ate them in the morning.)
I ate a lot in the morning...
- because I needed to move. - You ate a lot in the morning.
I added a bit this time.
(She eats glass noodles in the evening as well.)
Tofu is tasty when you tear it like that.
- She tears it with her hands. - You do it with your hands.
- They absorb the soup well. - They look like soft tofu.
- They absorb the soup quickly. - That's a plus.
(The jjigae is ready.)
(She seasons the julienned radish as the glass noodles cook.)
- That's salted shrimp. Yes. - Is that salted shrimp?
Let's add a bit of rice syrup.
I don't add sugar.
- You don't add sugar. - I don't add sugar.
Let's add chili powder.
I add chili powder.
- I add sesame oil and garlic. - It looks delicious.
- It's bound to be tasty. - It looks amazing.
(Shin Young massages the ingredients with her hands.)
My goodness.
- It looks delicious. - Seriously.
(Humming)
- I'm humming by myself. - It's the definition of happiness.
The cooking process is nice.
- It's therapeutic to watch. - I know.
(Salivating)
(She tries a bit.)
It looks like she is stealing food.
It's tasty.
- It looks delicious. - The flavors fill the mouth.
(My goodness)
Should I star in "Culinary Class Wars?"
I'm sorry.
You'll make it to the team match. I'm serious.
- Are you serious? - Glass Noodle Addict.
Glass Noodle Addict!
(Glass Noodle Addict, Eats glass noodles for every meal)
It's so tasty.
Gosh, it's so tasty.
(She's absorbed in the taste, but she still cleans up well.)
(She washes the dirty dishes right away.)
I don't feel lazy when I clean up right away.
(She puts away the condiments as well.)
I won't have to look for them when I put things back.
- Right. - Since I know that,
I keep thinking about the future.
Right.
I think that is why things are kept clean...
- even when there are many things. - Right.
(Peeking)
(It's already 7pm.)
Okay.
(Opening)
How many times are you opening the fridge in a single day?
I didn't open it that much.
(She takes out the frozen rice.)
It's too small.
(Torn)
It does look really small.
(They get put into the microwave after a lot of thought.)
But two containers were put in.
- Right. - Did you see that?
(Did you see that?)
The containers did look really small.
- Come on! - I expected two containers.
- Right. - Right.
(She sets the table with the food she made after that.)
I had to set the table with great food.
(Even the hot cheonggukjang gets moved.)
Gosh, that was darn hot.
(She takes out the heated up rice containers with both hands.)
(She places everything together nicely.)
- Gosh! - Gosh, it's cheonggukjang.
(Radish cheonggukjang and spicy radish)
- Cheongdo's water parsley. - Cheongdo's water parsley.
(The food for watching baseball at home is ready.)
I prefer a home meal like this instead of chicken and beer.
It feels like the cafeteria of the players.
(Moving)
(The TV is moved as well.)
- Gosh, it's the perfect setup... - Let's watch it now.
- to watch baseball. - Right.
(During breakfast or dinner...)
Thank you for the meal.
Even the mothers of the players don't watch this much baseball.
This is a treat that can be enjoyed for being diligent.
- Right. - It really is.
(She takes a bite of the stew first.)
(Letting out the steam)
(Satisfied)
It was so hot. It felt like my the roof of my mouth...
was going to get burned by the tofu's warmth.
You'll have to tear out the blisters afterwards.
(Hold on.)
(She picks up the glass noodles first.)
Like an aperitif, I started with the glass noodles.
An aperitif?
(Just like in the morning)
I'm curious how glass noodles would taste with cheonggukjang.
Gosh!
- That tastes so good. - You're addicted to glass noodles.
(Satisfied)
(Focused)
Unlike what I thought,
she's not watching much of the baseball.
- I was listening. - Right.
- I was listening to everything... - Baseball fans...
- that was happening. - listen to what's going on.
- You don't watch it with your eyes. - I'm aware of everything.
Even still, you really aren't watching the screen that much.
This is when she watches the screen.
It's when she turns her head to lift the chopsticks.
When she cools off the food that's hot.
- When the food is hot. - Right.
Just at that moment when she puts in the food.
After blowing on the food.
Blowing on the food and coming back down again.
(She picks up the hot glass noodles.)
I watched it for a brief moment.
- You watched it. - I watched it, didn't I?
(Her eyes are stuck on the food unless she's cooling it.)
I should've added in a bit more of the glass noodles.
(Disappointed)
(Slurping)
(She puts down the plate of glass noodles she's done with.)
All right. This is the second course now.
White rice.
My favorite white rice.
(She starts her meal in earnest with white rice.)
(Scooping)
(She wets the rice with the soup.)
It will go in here.
- I mixed it together. - Gosh, that looks good.
It's a small container of rice.
The cheonggukjang looks really good.
(She takes a bite after diligently mixing it.)
(Yelling)
(Disappointed)
(She clears up a bowl of rice as if nothing happened.)
(Getting up)
(The container she finished with gets put into the sink right away.)
- While you are eating? - She went right away.
I just rinsed it with water.
Shall I start my meal in earnest?
- What? - Was there something else?
Shall I start my meal...
- What? - in earnest?
- Was there something else? - So there are different courses.
There are different courses.
- Right. - Courses 1, 2, 3, 4.
I can't help it.
(Rice gets put into a brass bowl.)
- Why was the spicy radish there? - Gosh!
- It's for that reason! - That looks so good!
- Gosh, it's making me drool. - Spicy radish is love.
That looks so good.
The rice containers were tiny.
It was like bird feed. The rice containers were this small.
- What kind of bird eats that much? - I put in one whole container.
I had an original meal with one small container.
I put in some spicy radish in a brass bowl.
People love food made by their mom or dad.
But my food is the best to me.
It's amazing.
What an abundant life.
Stop being on a diet, everyone.
She's showing us how it's done.
Nice.
I'll add in some cheonggukjang.
The cheonggukjang is added.
Gosh, that looks so good.
- Gosh. - Gosh, that looks amazing.
Gosh.
Gosh!
(Picking up)
(She places the water parsley neatly.)
(She places rice on top of the water parsley wrap.)
So that's made into a wrap.
(She takes a great big bite.)
(Touched)
Try eating it like that, everyone.
- As a wrap like that? - With some water parsley.
- Right. Twirl up the water parsley. - Hey, Shin Young.
You're not watching the game at all!
I watched it a while ago.
- I watched it a while ago. - Who is batting right now?
- The Lions. - The jersey feels like an apron.
- Right. - In case she spills food.
- I watched it. - An apron?
- It will be washed afterwards. - Right.
That spoon appeared the most today.
(Bulgogi, seaweed soup, cheonggukjang, and other dishes)
- Right. - That is all I can remember.
That spoon is quite spacious.
I love how it's wide and deep.
(She's focusing on the spoon instead of the baseball game.)
Gosh, it's so good.
(Slurping)
(Without thinking about the baseball game, )
(she's only focusing on her meal.)
Gosh, there's no more.
- She's disappointed. - I should control myself.
(She scrapes until the last grain of rice.)
Gosh, she finished all of that.
I was controlling myself. It was a controlled meal.
Gosh, that was great.
(She ends her dinner meal while controlling herself.)
Gosh, that was a great meal.
(The used dishes get put into the sink.)
Gosh, that was a happy meal.
I felt so satisfied.
- You looked really happy. - You looked really happy.
She's watching baseball now.
I turned it around.
(She heads to the sink after turning the TV.)
- While doing the dishes? - Right. While doing the dishes.
Gosh, that's the best.
Nice. The bases are loaded.
(Her hands are quick...)
(and her eyes are fixed on the baseball game.)
(She cleans up while being entertained.)
Done!
(She hurries over to the living room.)
(I must carry on watching the baseball game.)
(Grabbing)
(She gets some rest after getting everything done.)
Gosh, my back.
(Heave-ho!)
She's feeling guilty!
(Embarrassed)
Right!
Okay.
Nice.
We have to score with this chance.
(Shin Young lies down for the first time in 8 hours.)
(Getting up)
- What is that? - What is that?
There were sweet potato chips.
Sweet potato chips?
I've never seen sweet potato chips kept in a couch.
It has cabinets. I made the most of them.
Sweet potato chips on one side, and cheese chips on the other.
- Everything is in place for you. - That's right.
Also, there are trash cans on both sides.
- Gosh. - When I'm lying on this side,
I can throw it away on this side.
When I'm lying on that side, I can throw it away on that side.
- This scene is pure happiness. - Right.
(Pure happiness)
(Sliding in)
- What are you doing? - It must be something good.
- Why are you eating so secretly? - Why are you eating like that?
What? Why are you eating like that?
The crumbs!
- In case the crumbs fall. - It's to hold the crumbs.
- In case the crumbs fall. - You eat like an otter.
(You eat like an otter.)
I should sit up.
Safe!
(Screaming)
It's here!
Nice!
(Well done!)
(Satisfied)
That's amazing.
I feel the happiest right now.
I love today the most, and I enjoy today the most.
When tomorrow comes, I will feel happy tomorrow.
My house is my own world. My country.
It's a place where I feel comfortable.
I can feel like I'm in a different country.
It's like my own globe.
A new world unfolds before me.
I feel happy that I'm safe and sound.
I can eat...
and do the things I want to do.
(I can eat and do the things I want to do.)
I started feeling very grateful at one point.
I used to be really stingy with myself.
"Gosh, this tastes so good!"
I wasn't able to say these things.
But this thought came into mind.
"Instead of being acknowledged by others,"
"wouldn't it be better for me to acknowledge myself?"
I think it's only a very thin line...
between a tragedy and a comedy in people's minds.
Gosh, what a game!
Nice! That was perfect.
That was great.
How did it feel to watch your life?
I feel a lot more at ease now.
- Right. - It feels comfortable...
to lay everything down.
I want to make the most of my life even more.
There are so many fun things in life.
I've been wondering why I've been...
wasting my time at home in the past.
- After going through those times, - Right.
I think she has learned...
how to become a friend for herself.
Right.
This was what I was really impressed with.
She decided to go on a diet...
- and maintained that for 13 years. - Right.
When she gets hooked on something, she makes the most out of it.
- She makes the most out of it. - Right.
- Right. That's what she's like. - That's hard to do.
- Right. - I have to reach the end of it.
- You're so impressive. - I want to copy you...
- and do the things you did. - That would be great.
Shin Young looks much brighter and happier.
We'll continue to root for you. Thank you!
Thank you!
(I Live Alone)
(Busy Day of Cooking)
"Busy Day of Cooking?"
(A crowded place)
(It's Hongdae, the street of youth.)
- What? - Gosh.
- You went there? - Hongdae?
Well, it's close to where I live.
(Woo Il heads somewhere with a bag that is as big as his upper body.)
- Hello! - Hello!
Hello. Drive safely.
(Chuckling)
- Hello. - Hello.
(He greets another person.)
I think it has been around 13 years since I lived in this area.
I see a lot of young university students.
Shall I say it energizes me?
Right. There's a certain vibe in Hongdae.
(Gosh, it's Mr. Nice.)
They're taking selfies. What's wrong with you?
Gosh.
At the crosswalk?
They're taking selfies. What are you doing?
(After showing his fan service that wasn't wanted, )
(he heads somewhere.)
(He walks in naturally.)
Hello.
- Hello. - Hello.
(He greets everyone naturally.)
- What? - Hello.
It's a kitchen.
This is the cooking school which I attend...
twice a week these days.
- You attend a cooking school? - Yes.
I wanted to start something at the start of this year.
One of the things I considered was cooking.
I realized that...
I didn't know how to cook anything.
While working these days,
cooking felt like something I couldn't leave out.
"Do you know how to cook something, Woo Il?"
"Are you good at cooking?"
I got asked these questions really often.
When I said I couldn't cook,
I didn't get any calls after that.
This happened quite a few times to me.
There's a certain feeling...
- that you might be a good cook. - Right.
That made me think that I should know how to...
cook a few dishes.
It was something that could be related to my work as well.
It has been a month since I attended.
I go twice a week.
I'm there for around four hours during each session.
(He's working hard to learn twice a week for 4 hours.)
(He's passionate enough to burn up the frying pan.)
You have to be careful with your hair.
(Woo Il is burning with passion for cooking.)
It was my first time applying for classes...
after attending cram school when I was 20 years old.
There was a touching moment.
It was my mother's birthday on the day I had class.
I gave my mother the food I made...
and she felt very touched.
- Gosh. - Gosh.
(Good son Woo Il's perspective)
This was what my mom said.
"I get to experience a day like this after living a long life."
"I didn't expect to eat the food you made."
That felt...
quite strange.
"You just need to get married now." Did she not say that afterward?
She did say that.
- Of course, she did. - Really?
"What's the point of making this for yourself?"
She kept saying those things.
"This is so much food."
"You'll end up throwing it away."
"If you cook for yourself,"
"you'll throw out half of it."
"You should know not to waste ingredients."
"You must have your own family."
"You must feel so lonely to eat this on your own."
It sparked a fire.
(He ties up his hair before class begins.)
- That's important. - Of course.
- Hygiene is the most important. - Right.
I got some drinks for everyone.
This is for everyone.
- I got drinks for everyone. - The students?
For the students as well.
I got you juice just in case you don't like coffee.
- Thank you. - This was the most expensive one.
This was the most expensive one.
Our class is a hobby class.
It's focused on home meals.
We learn simple dishes that can be made at home...
during our sessions.
As for the age group, there are really young students...
and seniors as well.
I didn't know there were so many people...
who wanted to learn how to cook in Korea.
That's great. It's a comfortable setting as well.
There are many people who want to learn how to cook.
(After sharing drinks with everyone, )
(Woo Il gets something out of the bag he brought.)
It has already begun.
- It has already begun... - Right.
With the preparations.
(He sets his station naturally.)
What number was it for that class?
That was my ninth class.
(It's already his 9th class.)
If you're ready, come to the front...
- with the recipe. - Right.
Come to the front.
All right. Today,
- we'll make the Andong jjimdak. - Jjimdak?
They'll be making jjimdak?
Steamed mussels and rice cake?
We'll make the rolled omelet as well as we will have enough time.
This class was quite difficult.
- Right? - Right. The chicken...
has to be prepared.
Right. She knows.
We'll start with the Andong jjimdak.
You each have been given a whole chicken.
You must make the cuts and remove the innards.
Potatoes, carrots, and onions.
We'll use sweet potatoes as well. Cut them into big pieces.
The order of the vegetables that are put in...
starts with the ones that need some time to get cooked.
I won't remove the skin for the sweet potatoes.
The sweet potatoes get mushy when they get cooked,
so put them in with the skin.
They will be used as big chunks.
- Around this size. - Why is the skin kept?
The jjimdak gets boiled for a long time.
That's to prevent the sweet potatoes from becoming mushy.
This is cut into similar pieces as well.
Like this. It's good to sort out the edges for this as well.
Cut them from top to bottom.
This prevents the potato from becoming mushy.
Why are the potatoes put into water?
Because of enzymatic browning,
potatoes change in color when met with metal or air.
- It's the same for this. - That was a great question.
- A sharp question. - That was very sharp.
For that reason,
it's best to slice it right after it's prepared.
You don't press down when slicing these.
Pressing down will bring out the juice.
You will lose all of the flavor.
Use the push cutting technique.
- You must use the blade. - They must be round pieces.
There are many details that must be learned...
beyond just the recipe.
When cutting vegetables,
there are many different methods of cutting them.
It's different for each dish.
It's hard to remember all of those details.
It looks easy from afar,
- It's never easy. - but it's hard once you try.
When you're done with this, the water will start boiling.
That is when you prepare the chicken.
Remove the blood that is just on the outside.
When you open it up, you'll find the innards.
You must remove the innards.
There's a hard part in the middle. Go around it.
It looks easy from afar.
There's a bone right here.
It will be hard to cut when you place the knife here.
That is why you go around it. These parts will be removed later.
Like this.
It will be cut easily like this.
Remove the cartilage.
It looks like he has missed quite a few parts already.
It's all set.
To the boiling water...
In Korean cuisine, we call it "splashing" in the water.
Once it starts boiling, the impurities rise.
(Super focused)
Now, add onions and...
This is for one serving.
Now, let's wrap it up.
- It looks good. - It must be good.
- It looks good. - Yes, it will be good.
- Add it, and that's all. - All right.
That's it.
(Woo Il is back to his station.)
(Checking the recipe once again)
Today's menu is too hard.
I think it'll be harder if you cook there.
It is hard.
(Let's start for now.)
If you miss a step, then it'll get messed up.
(Shall I begin?)
(Grabbing the potato first)
(Determined)
(He begins to peel it without hesitation.)
(Focused)
(Next, he prepares dried chili, )
(shiitake mushroom, )
(carrots.)
He's working so hard.
(Woo Il prepares the vegetables quite skillfully.)
Actually, I...
I did cook a little when I was in the military.
I cooked for a group of 30 soldiers...
for 6 months. I made all 3 meals every day...
and fed them.
(Dignified)
- What is that? - Is he an armed infiltrating agent?
- In Gangwon Province. - An armed infiltrating agent?
What was the number for reporting a spy?
When I was in the military stationed at a GOP,
I worked as the cook's assistant for about 4 to 5 months.
Was their evaluation okay?
- How did they react? - They all enjoyed it.
- Oh, really? - Yes.
They said I was really good at cooking.
They complimented me a lot.
Yes.
(Almost Became a Legendary Military Cook)
(Knife work of a former expertise)
(Burning with confidence)
(He easily prepared the basic ingredients.)
(Next, it's time to make a sauce.)
Getting the right seasoning and thickness is really hard.
(He looks like a master from the look on his face.)
(Doing it on his own in order)
(He quickly finishes making a sauce for seasoning.)
It's really convenient if you remember how to make seasoning.
For the Korean Cuisine Culinary Technician Certification Exam,
- it goes by s, s, g, g, p, s, s. - That's right.
- Oh, right. - The basic seasoning.
It's also the order in terms of amount.
They memorize it like chemical symbols.
I often use s, s, v.
- Vinegar? - Soy sauce, sugar, vinegar.
That's all I use.
And I never taste my food when I cook.
- Why not? - Only cowards do.
That's right.
You can't taste your food when you take the exam.
- It shows how skilled you are. - That's right.
- I was already practicing it. - Your points get deducted?
- That's right. - I've already realized it.
(Mysterious)
(Woo Il has already made seasoning after prepping vegetables.)
What should I do next?
Gosh, this is the hard part.
(It's time to prepare the chicken.)
This is the hard one.
It looked easy when she did it.
(Looking at the chicken)
(Looking around)
It feels like...
- he'd take a bite as is. - A bite like this.
The backdrop will change...
- to a mountain. - After it changes...
Like gnawing the meat without your master knowing.
- After getting flogged. - "You brat!"
"I'm sorry, my lord."
"I was too starved."
(It suits him so well.)
(Like a servant who stole a chicken behind his master)
(Snooping around)
(His classmates are proceeding smoothly.)
(Skillfully preparing the drumsticks)
They all knew how to handle it.
(They're all so good.)
(Lifting the knife after plucking up his courage)
When I was about to face it,
- I guess you can cut it randomly. - I didn't know what to do.
I was lost.
That's right.
Should I open its belly?
That's right. Make the chicken breast face up.
Or does it face down?
I think you should put it upside down.
- The middle... - The neck should face down, right?
It doesn't matter if you put it the other way around.
Cut it like this.
That part must be soft, so it should be cut well.
- Just cut the middle. - I can just cut it like this?
Cut it and spread it like a butterfly.
Be careful. It's slippery.
(Let's go.)
- Like this. - Gosh, that's unstable.
If you put your knife in like this, it slips.
Put it in like this.
(The knife bounces out without penetrating.)
Normally, the tips of knives are really sharp,
so if you put the tip in first... It's sharp.
- You have to stab it first. - Yes. Then it's easier.
If it doesn't cut easily.
You should've told me.
- There's a bone. - That's right.
- Use your strength. Yes. - Oh, at once like this?
Yes, so it can spread.
Once it spreads open, you'll find the backbone.
Check the cartilage too.
(Check the cartilage?)
- Should I cut it like this? - That's right.
Otherwise, you cut it wrong.
Where is the cartilage?
Try putting in your thumb.
- This way? - You'll feel it in here.
- Where should I put it in? - Over here.
The sunken part.
- Oh, here? - Here.
- It's around the armpit. - Yes, put it in there.
Try slashing it as you cut.
(The armpit...)
- So... - I should give it a try.
She said it was the sunken part.
That's where the cartilage is.
- But every part is sunken. - That's right.
It's all sunken.
If you bend your finger, you can see that this is the cartilage.
If you bend it backward...
- Bend it backward, and... - Oh, bend the leg backward?
Then you can remove the bones completely.
Oh, you have to bend it backward.
Then you just need to cut the boneless part.
That's really easy to understand.
(I can't find the cartilage.)
You're checking its pulse.
You're massaging the chicken.
- You do that for an upset stomach. - Can't it digest well?
- That's right. - Why do you keep pressing that?
The chicken must have an upset stomach.
It must have a sudden indigestion.
You're the only one who's like Heo Jun there.
Softly.
(Woo Il's hand is healing.)
(Woo Il was massaging the chicken with all his effort.)
(Glancing over)
(Glancing over again)
(Excuse me, ma'am...)
This one...
- This one... - It must be connected there.
- Where is the cartilage? - Between the thigh meat.
I don't think it has a cartilage.
It does.
- Is this it? - If you press it hard,
it could be crushed, so use a knife next time.
That's right. It's like that.
Cut the thigh separately.
The backbone can be cut.
- Oh, here? - Yes.
Remove the fat around the neck.
- Then slice it. - It's not easy.
It's really hard when it's your first time.
It must be really hard.
(Struggling)
It takes forever to prepare the chicken.
(He took a long time to prepare the chicken.)
(Glancing over)
(Hold on. The others are...)
(They're already moving into the final phase.)
(Woo Il has only the cleaned chicken on his table.)
(Anxious)
You feel really anxious if you're the only one falling behind.
(He anxiously checks the recipe.)
This is when speed matters.
(Boiling the chicken)
Pour out the water.
(Pour out the water used to boil the chicken for the first time.)
(Entering the chicken in the fresh water)
(Quickly pouring the seasoning)
While jjimdak is being cooked,
we'll make a rolled omelet.
(We're making a rolled omelet now?)
Everyone was done and waiting for me.
Oh, no.
Mine wasn't ready,
but I had to make a rolled omelet,
so I broke down.
(My jjimdak isn't ready yet.)
(Let's put everything in for now.)
Now, please come to the front again.
(Trudging after adding the vegetables to the pot)
We'll now make steamed mussels and rice cake...
and a rolled omelet.
I've never heard of steamed mussels and rice cake.
What we need for the rolled omelet is five eggs...
and three different vegetables that are minced.
Grab this and roll it.
Grab it diagonally and flip it.
Make the pan bounce too.
(Like this)
Now, to the steamed mussels and rice cake...
Be careful not to get splashed.
(I see.)
As for mussels, you can find aquatic plants in them.
Just remove these only.
Then rub it.
There's no soup for this dish.
- There's no soup. - Oh, it's like that.
It's like tteokbokki.
You'll try it now.
(Preparing to make a rolled omelet)
Pouring it in the pan is easy.
- The next part is the hard one. - Rolling it is hard.
- Rolling is the difficult part. - Rolling requires a skill.
(Let's go for it.)
(Carefully pouring it into the pan)
- Controlling the fire is important. - That's right.
You need to do it well. Make it thin.
The amount you pour...
- must be important too. - Yes, to make it even.
- You can't pour too much. - All right.
Go back and forth horizontally.
Tilt it a little and roll it. One, two, three.
(It's time to roll the omelet.)
(Now, it's the real thing.)
Give it a try. One, two, three.
I think that part will tear. Oh, no.
- You did that at once. - He'll make a huge omelet today.
One, two, three. I think that part will tear.
Oh, no.
(Folding the omelet without holding back)
It's like a crepe.
Yes, like that. Then push it.
(Rolling it with all his body)
Wait.
(In tatters)
(Should I just give up cooking?)
You need to put the chopsticks diagonally...
- so it wouldn't tear. - That's correct.
You're indeed good.
She's a chef.
- Si Hyeon is a chef. - I know.
The instructor said the exact same thing.
Put the chopsticks diagonally so it wouldn't have a hole.
- Diagonally. - That's right.
(I see.)
I think it's too much for me to make three dishes.
I think it's too hard.
Making three dishes is too hectic.
(Agreeing)
Since you need to wash the dishes too,
finish the dishes...
until 6:30pm.
What? I haven't made that yet.
There's another class afterward,
so we need to clean up and leave.
(They have only 15 minutes.)
(The other classmates are making the last dish already.)
While I was making a rolled omelet,
the rest of them were done.
(Glancing over)
It's okay to do the last roll well only.
(It's his last chance.)
As long as you do the final roll well...
- Yes, the shape... - The last one.
One, two, three. Flip it lightly.
Yes. You saved it.
- You saved it. - Nice!
(He saved the rolled omelet with all his body.)
You can just do the last roll well.
(Feeling proud)
Please wrap up your dishes within ten minutes.
(In 10 minutes?)
You haven't started making steamed mussels and rice cake.
Please wrap up your dishes within ten minutes.
(In 10 minutes?)
You haven't started making steamed mussels and rice cake.
(The other classmates are wrapping up already.)
- She looks like an expert. - Right. She's good.
(He hasn't even started on the next dish.)
(Woo Il is feeling rushed.)
- Oh, no! - What is it?
(Splash)
The bag...
(He put the whole thing in the bag as he felt rushed.)
(Flapping)
(Upset)
(As he doesn't have time, )
(he quickly moves on to the next step.)
How do I clean mussels?
Just rub it hard.
You need to remove the threads.
(Busy)
He's working faster.
I know. I felt even more rushed.
(Taking out the boiled rice cakes)
(Putting it in the bowl right away as he's rushed)
Now, please wrap up...
- in five minutes. - It drove me crazy.
- Five minutes? - Yes.
(This is bad.)
(Others are already washing their dishes.)
(Thinking hard)
He's become serious.
(Looking around)
(Sighing)
No way. This won't work.
(He checks the ingredients.)
It won't work.
(Heading somewhere after making a decision)
(Tearing)
You can tear that so well.
He's the best at that.
(Returning with the plastic bags he tore so well)
(He decides to pack the steamed mussels and rice cake.)
(Putting the hot rice cakes straight into the plastic bag)
(Taking it)
(Pouring)
What?
- You threw away the broth? - That's...
That was mussel soup.
(After throwing away the mussel broth, )
(he frantically packed the jjimdak as well.)
(Squeaky clean)
(I should do the dishes quickly, at least.)
(The classmate who's done goes home first.)
- She's the ace. - Oh, no.
- She seemed extraordinary. - She's leaving.
Everyone else was leaving when I was washing the dishes.
So I felt more rushed.
(I felt rushed.)
(Woo Il quickly wrapped it up.)
- Great work. - Good job.
- Have a good day. - See you next time.
- See you. Great job. - Bye.
(Sighing)
(Trudging)
(It's gotten dark outside already.)
It must've been tiring.
- It must've drained you. - I was exhausted.
You were there for more than three hours, right?
Three hours and a half to four hours.
(I worked hard today again.)
Your day's gone.
(Opening)
(Sighing)
(He trudged back home.)
(Turning on the lights as soon as he's home)
(He's free from the cooking bag...)
(that's been weighing down his shoulders.)
(Sighing)
(Feeling more fatigue as his tension relaxes)
(Flopping onto the sofa)
I think it's harder than working out for three hours.
- It is exhausting. - That's right.
Seriously, I...
Doing something in the field you're not familiar with is not easy.
But as I learned to cook,
I kept getting reminded of my mom.
- That's right. - I thought, "How did she..."
- "do this all her life?" - That's right.
You come to realize that as you cook.
- Seriously. - It could seem like a simple dish,
but it takes a lot of effort.
There's no such thing as a simple dish.
- There's no such thing. - You're right.
(Woo Il is worn out and exhausted like a sock with a hole.)
(Gosh, let's collect myself.)
(Dragging his worn-out self to the kitchen)
(Bumping his head)
(He doesn't even have the energy to feel the pain.)
(Opening his fridge)
(Filled with leftover food)
(He's saved even the smallest bit.)
It looks exactly like mine.
I think food is like clothes.
That's what food means to me.
I'd think, "Wouldn't I have a bite of this one day?"
That's why I freeze everything and keep them in the fridge.
That's true.
With the same thought, I had the meat in the freezer,
and I got a stomachache.
- Just don't do it. - For real though,
I don't know what I froze in the freezer.
You shouldn't do it.
- You get a stomachache. - So I realize what it is...
after I microwave it.
- To learn the original form of it? - Yes.
- A blind dish. - A microwave is like...
a time machine for you.
I've always lived like this,
but after I started learning to cook, it's been bothering me.
I kept thinking of cleaning up the fridge.
I've only had such a thought,
then I realized I shouldn't push it off any longer.
"I should clean it up." That's why I started on it.
(Let's clean up the fridge for real!)
(Let's take them all out first.)
(Ingredients keep coming out like a magic treasure jar.)
I wanted to clean all of them up.
It's really tiring to clean up a fridge.
(Piled up)
(Taking out the plastic cups he's been collecting)
- He's finally throwing them. - Finally.
(There were always plastic cups in his fridge.)
(He drank the leftover coffees from his fridge endless times.)
(Woo Il has changed.)
(Pushing the cup in)
- That's... - Are those two your favorites?
They're not my favorite,
but I just couldn't throw out everything.
Around a week ago,
a little kid was walking past me in my apartment complex.
He asked, "Do you really keep the takeout coffees in your fridge..."
"and keep drinking them?"
I said, "Yes, I do."
He went, "That's not good for your health. Don't do that."
Then he went home.
- He's smart. - After hearing him,
I realized I should really throw them out.
- We've said that about 30 times. - I know. A little kid said that...
I've said it 40 times.
I could relate to it more because a kid said it.
- "Even kids are worried about me." - Yes.
(Let's see.)
January, 2026.
Goodness, it's expired.
September 9, 2025?
February 12, 2026.
(Boldly throwing out the items that are expired)
You shouldn't have the ingredients that are expired.
- You shouldn't. - Right. You shouldn't.
(Boldly throwing out the items that are expired)
(Let's throw out the old makgeolli too.)
Makgeolli?
(Hissing)
Darn it.
(The makgeolli exploded like a celebratory champagne.)
Why is there so much?
(Oh, no!)
- Gosh. - Oh, no!
Darn it.
(It splashed all over me.)
It'd have been better to keep it in the fridge.
Oh, no.
(He's forced to clean the kitchen as well.)
(Wiping it clean)
(Taking something out)
(I should have what I made today for dinner.)
That's stir-fried squid.
That's fresh kimchi. I made it.
- That looks delicious. - Gosh.
(Having jjimdak he made today as dinner)
You can make lots of different dishes now.
(In the past, he wasn't familiar with cooking.)
(His meals were filled with frozen food.)
(His meal has changed into homemade food with warmth.)
Seeing that makes me feel proud.
It's been upgraded a lot.
(He finally tastes it.)
(Taking a big bite)
(Nodding)
(Taking another big bite)
It looks nice.
It's really nice.
I was even surprised myself. It was that good.
I didn't know the food I made...
could be that good.
I don't think it has a cartilage.
When I learn cooking in the class, it's hectic.
I'm busy following her instructions.
But after I tried the dish I made,
I felt proud of myself.
I think it also makes me feel good to make food for myself.
Now, I'm confident to make...
any dishes if there's a recipe.
- Really? - Yes.
That's really nice.
(Grabbing the remote control)
How to make delicious jjimdak.
Soak it in milk first.
- Are you reviewing it? - It'll be more fun to watch it...
- after knowing a thing or two. - That's right.
It's different.
(Super focused)
And then...
(Let's Live Well)
(Next story)
(Gosh, my back...)
Goodness.
Gosh, my leg.
(His leg is bruised all over.)
(Goodness)
(Like the body of a soldier who's fought 100 wars)
(Currently, I'm doing...)
(the cross-country march across the nation.)
(He challenged himself to the cross-country march in his 20s.)
(He failed because he developed plantar fasciitis.)
(He challenged himself to the cross-country march again...)
(before he gets any older.)
(He starts the journey from his home in Seoul.)
(His final destination is Gwangalli, Busan.)
(After his friend died, )
(he got consoled every time he walked.)
(Let's go!)
(To Busan for 16 days)
(The total distance he walked)
(420km)
(It's finally the last day.)
(I think I should challenge my limits.)
(The most important thing is mental strength.)
(It's been 17 days since he started.)
(Sung Hwan's challenge is finally coming to an end.)
(Gosh, what do I do?)
(Victory is just within reach.)
(Will I be able to complete the journey?)
(A Grueling March Across the Country)
(With her sweet and scary acting as a ghost in "Guardian,")
(she became the nation's favorite scene-stealer.)
(Her presence stands out even among great actors.)
("Every Hit Movie Has Actress Park Gyeong Hye")
(From "Smugglers" to "Dr. Cheon and Lost Talisman")
(In reality, )
(she's a newbie who just started living alone.)
(Actress Park Gyeong Hye)
(It's her first independent home.)
(I invite you to my home sweet home.)
(The interior design is quite antique.)
(My house needs a little fixing.)
(She even made eye contact with mold.)
(There's nothing that can't be solved.)
(Even if it's hard, get it done bravely.)
Even though I don't own this place...
(Even though I don't own it, I live in it anyway.)
(I can do it!)
(Welcome.)
(Laughing)
(It's been 2 years since she started doing the part-time job.)
(The stable income that protects...)
(Gyeong Hye's life and dream.)
(I love my current life.)
(Great job.)
Well done.
(Just-beginning Independent Life)